It's not too tight, is it?
No.
Pardon me.
Master, you have a guest.
Dedd Marlay, Governor-General of Holjoy?
Oh, right, that up-and-comer
from my fief.
I'll be right there. Let him in.
Understood.
The royal family has a custom
of granting fiefs to princes
so that they can learn
about government affairs.
For that reason, the people of each fief
revere the prince serving as their
lord as if he were a monarch.
This man, who was born in Almeria
but now works in a land called Holjoy,
is no exception.
Dedd Marlay
Governor-General of Holjoy
Dedd Marlay.
It is truly a pleasure to
stand in your royal presence.
No need for such formalities.
Have a seat.
At once.
This is the second time we've met.
Yes.
I introduced myself to you
about a year and a half ago,
when the emperor appointed
me as governor-general.
How has it been going?
As I recall, you were given an imperial
order to manage flood control in Holjoy.
I can see it isn't going well.
Holjoy is a fertile grain-producing
region in the bend of a large river,
but it suffers from flooding on occasion.
The emperor appointed Marlay of Almeria,
the home of the Water Clan, to govern
it in hopes that he could stabilize it.
What is the problem?
Well, we haven't received any funding,
and we can't use money we don't have.
Funding? You must have some.
It was an imperial order.
Yes, it was,
but the Home Ministry keeps
coming up with excuses...
So that's it.
Your Highness?
Follow me.
To what do I owe this unexpected
visit, Prince Noah?
Maverick
Minister of Finance
Marlay told me that you've been
delaying the distribution of his funds.
I most certainly have not.
Then why won't you give him the money?
Well, you see, there is a
very good reason for that.
If you're going to say a child
wouldn't understand, be silent.
But of course I wouldn't
say something so rude.
Then explain yourself.
With pleasure.
Holjoy suffered flood damage
yet again last year.
Our kind emperor's heart
hurt so badly for them
that he granted them a whole
year of tax exemption.
It always comes back to this...
And?
That means they have leftover tax money.
It is the Ministry of Finance's
opinion that they should use that.
Do you understand now?
I see.
Are you belittling me?
They had a flood, so the emperor
gave them a tax exemption.
Why? Because they had no money to pay.
It was kind of him, but that
itself is the core of the issue.
You talk as if they have that money.
I'll ask again: are you belittling me?
Th-That is not what I meant!
Explain, then.
Well... the truth is, I can't
send them money right now.
Why not?
The emperor's...
Yes!
You are aware of the plan to build
the emperor's summer retreat, yes?
Yes.
The emperor is not young anymore.
He should spend his summers
not in the hot capital,
but in a land that's just
a little bit cooler.
But, although it's only a retreat,
it's for the emperor's use,
so naturally, it will be a royal villa!
In short, we must build a city
that he can call his villa!
And that requires a vast amount of money.
If he's bringing the emperor into this...
Surely you understand now!
It's all we can do to give the emperor—
Silence.
You're committing a grave crime
against the royal family.
"This flooded region needs flood
control, but we're building a villa,
so we can't spare the money."
That is what you're telling me.
Do you take my father for a fool?
Y-You misunderstand!
You misunderstand me!
I meant nothing of the sort!
Then distribute the funds.
Or shall I go and appeal
to the emperor myself?
Certainly not!
I will supply Holjoy with
funding right away!
B-But, Minister...
And what are you just
standing around for?!
Go! This gets top priority!
Y-Yes, sir!
Move it!
What an amazing young man.
He got the Minister of Finance to
yield without lifting a finger!
You have my utmost admiration.
The way you negotiate is brilliant.
You caught him in his gaffes and
contradictions with your verbal mastery.
I am ashamed that I was foolish
enough to put you in this position.
And then you unleashed
that masterful assault...
I see. He thought that
because I'm a prince,
he could use me to force
his demands through.
There is naught I can do but
fall prostrate before you.
I will hurry back and proceed
with the flood control measures.
Good.
I bring a message!
I bring a message for
the Thirteenth Prince.
His Majesty has summoned you.
He asks you to come and
see him in person.
The emperor?
Born Blessed, So I'll Obtain Ultimate Power
Episode 3
Those Gained, Those Lost
Noah Ararat.
I have come in response to your summons.
Ah, you're here. You can relax.
Thank you, sire.
Allow me to start by saying, "Well done."
I'm talking about Holjoy.
I hear you thoroughly routed Maverick.
That only just happened!
How does he know?
Information is a weapon,
and one you should make a
habit of keeping polished.
Yes, sire... but I only did
what anyone would have.
Indeed... but what comes naturally
does not come easily.
There are many slick tongues out
there who know how to use flattery.
Not many people can do the
right thing with natural ease.
Most impressive for a boy of only six.
Stand.
Yes, sire.
So that is what Leviathan looks like now?
I see. It truly is smaller.
Yes.
Of course my mansion would also be
within his information network.
The idea that you have fully
mastered that magic sword—
considering its dark history—can
only be described as remarkable.
If I hadn't stopped it back then, it
would have killed everyone in that market.
A dark history, huh?
It would serve you well to learn
the techniques to wield it.
I've summoned an instructor
of swordsmanship.
Damion Noble
Kingdom's Greatest Swordsman
Damion Noble, at your service.
Noble is the empire's greatest swordsman.
It is said that there are
none who can match him.
You honor me.
Learn from him.
Yes, sire.
Your Highness.
If I may, I would like to
request a bout right away.
With a child who still knows nothing?
Not to worry. I will observe only
his aptitude, not his technique.
Very well.
He convinced my father.
He clearly has his trust.
If I may.
Now, come at me however you see fit.
Leviathan's memories
are flowing into me...
The memories of all its past owners.
Not bad!
Truly a magic sword that
chooses its own master.
Its previous owners must have
been very skilled, as well.
Your Majesty.
I sincerely apologize.
I have nothing to teach the prince.
His strength and speed are
indeed those of a child,
but he used technique alone to disarm me.
His Highness already possesses the
swordsmanship skill of a master.
It would be presumptuous
of me to try to teach him.
I am soundly defeated.
I see. So that's how it is.
Impressive! You truly
are something, Noah!
I know.
I will make you head judge in this
year's knight selection exam.
There is no one better
suited for the job.
What say you, Noah?
Understood. I will see this task through.
The knight selection exam
is an annual event involving participants
from all corners of the empire.
For this empire, a nation of warriors
that treasures its military,
it is said that the way of the warrior
is the only path to success by merit.
In the exam, the fighters who win
their regional preliminaries
meet in the capital for
their final battles.
The one who emerges victorious
earns the title of knight
and immediately joins the
upper ranks of society.
The first job of the new knight is to
become a subordinate of the head judge.
Thirteenth Imperial Prince Noah Ararat
Sex: Male
Level: 1
/
∞
HP: F
Fire: F
MP: F
Water: E+SS
Strength: F+F
Wind: F
Stamina: F+F
Earth: F
Intelligence: F
Light: F
Spirit: F
Dark: F
Speed: F
With a talented knight in my service,
I could become even stronger.
Then let me ask you this.
How shall Noah judge this event?
By either round-robin or elimination.
That is the first thing the
head judge must decide.
I have one request.
I want to do away with the
regional preliminaries
and do all the judging
here in the capital,
before my own eyes.
Why is that?
The empire is vast.
I can't observe all the
preliminaries in every region.
I wouldn't want any strong candidates
to be excluded for arbitrary reasons.
I don't want to overlook any talent.
Do as you please.
Yes, sire.
If you'll excuse me.
Zoey.
Yes?
Are there any knight selection exam
participants in your village?
Yes, one who is our simple
village's lone gateway to glory,
and the only one our village
sends to the exam every year.
I see.
I did away with the regional
preliminaries this year,
so they can send more if they like.
If it pleases you...
What is it?
Oh, nothing. I do apologize.
I'm not angry or anything.
I just want to know what you
were thinking. Tell me.
It's nothing of consequence, but...
The reason our village sends
only one challenger is because
we can't afford the travel
and lodging expenses.
Everything costs more in the capital,
so it takes donations from
all of us just to send one.
That one ends up shouldering
all of the village's hopes,
so they all get very serious about—
All right. I'll do away with that, too.
I want to choose from among
as many as possible.
It wouldn't do to overlook any
talent for such a reason.
I will cover all travel
and lodging expenses.
That... would make everyone
in our village very happy,
but wouldn't it cost a
great deal of money?
It doesn't mean arranging
everything from nothing.
Dylan.
I am here.
Find out how many vacant houses are
in the capital, and buy them all.
If that's enough, great.
If not, we'll build a dormitory of sorts.
Understood.
And then there's the matter of meals.
Talk to all the merchants
we have connections with.
I'll go out to town, as well.
Master, you are amazing!
This is my estimate.
This can't be right.
We're talking about food for
the duration of the exam.
This leaves you with a deep deficit.
Yes, but this is a request from
the Thirteenth Prince himself.
You're lying.
Merchants don't give money
away out of mere compassion.
What is it you want from me?
To think a boy your age, and a noble at
that, understands the world so well...
It's more like using money
wastefully is part of my job.
You never cease to amaze me.
Well? What do you want?
There is a palace employment exam
run on roughly the same scale
as the knight selection exam.
And, well... I was hoping you would
know what sorts of people are hired.
So you want to put a girl in the palace.
I get it.
If he had the support of
someone in the palace,
he'd be the first to hear
any new information.
And if she were to be ordered to spend
nights with the emperor as a consort,
the profits would be immeasurable.
Of course, this has nothing to
do with what you've asked of me.
I have already sent a token of
my gratitude to your mansion.
Advance payment, eh? Smart.
One condition.
Yes?
If it's a girl I like,
I'll put in a good word.
Thank you so much!
But it must be a girl
I sincerely approve of.
Of course. I will choose one who
measures up to your standards.
Your Highness...
Your kindness and keen perception,
for a man like me, elevate
you above all others.
Please allow me to
add the crest of the
Thirteenth Prince's house
to my store sign.
You will fully devote
yourself to my service?
Yes!
Know that I will not tolerate betrayal.
Accepting Byron as a subordinate
increased my stats.
HP: F
Fire: F
MP: F
Water: E+SS
Strength: F+F
Wind: F
Stamina: F+F
Earth: F
Intelligence: F+F
Light: F
Spirit: F+F
Dark: F
Speed: F
Dexterity: F+F
Luck F+F
If I keep this up, I
can get even stronger.
HP: F
Fire: F
MP: F
Water: E+SS
Strength: F+F
Wind: F
Stamina: F+F
Earth: F
Intelligence: F+F
Light: F
Fire: F
Water: E+S
Wind: F
Earth: F
One of my stats went down?!
The SS on Water...
Has something happened in Almeria?!
Zoey, I'm going to see the emperor!
Head for the palace!
Tell the driver! Now!
Y-Yes, master!
Hmm... A change in Almeria?
Yes.
How did you know?
The way he said that...
You know of it, then?
No.
I merely noticed the signs.
Then... what the signs indicated
has indeed come to pass.
Your Majesty.
Impressive, Noah.
Then...
Yes.
There has been a rebellion in Almeria.
How large do you believe it is?
Considering my SS just dropped to S,
it might look like it dropped by half,
but the reality is...
it only went down by one
rank out of several.
Fire
Water
Wind
Earth
Light
That means...
I believe it is small
in scale at the moment.
You are correct.
The report identified
five thousand rebels.
So I was right?
Their numbers are low,
and it's in your fief.
Noah, have you any intention
of putting it down yourself?
Unfortunately, I fear that is impossible.
Oh?
I am still young and
unfamiliar with combat.
I don't know whether the
soldiers would listen to me.
If we're to send a prince
to subjugate it,
I think it should be one
of my older brothers.
That is not the answer I expected.
You looked at the situation so
objectively before refusing.
Very well. I will stand by your
judgment and choose another.
Is there one you would recommend?
Of the princes, I believe
Henry is the best choice.
Why is that?
With such low numbers, the orthodox
approach is to suppress them head-on.
As the most prudent of my brothers,
I believe Henry is up to the task.
A fine choice.
Bring Henry to me!
Are you sure? This could
have been your chance.
The empire is a nation of warriors.
A great achievement in battle
now could benefit you later.
I am not well-learned enough
for such a sudden deployment.
Even if I survived, many soldiers
would likely die in vain.
Calm and collected as ever, I see.
They're here!
Stop the carriage!
What is it?!
Leviathan reacted to them.
It's me they're after.
I can't get my brother involved!
Noah!
Master!
Water users...
They're Almerian rebels.
Get him!
Impossible...
A child... like him...
Master!
Are you all right?!
Yes.
My goodness.
You've gotten even stronger in the
few days since I last saw you.
I'd heard that the rebel army
was centered around cavalrymen,
but I guess they had some like this, too.
If only we could have
interrogated them...
I didn't kill them.
After cutting them down,
I used Leviathan's threat
to knock them unconscious.
People like these are too
likely to kill themselves.
You're right...
They're all breathing.
I'll let you handle them.
More importantly...
Did you mention cavalrymen earlier?
Almeria does not have a strong
supply of war horses.
Correct.
You wanted to see me, Your Highness?
Yes.
You do business in the area
surrounding Almeria as well, yes?
Yes.
Consider yourself dead
if you tell anyone this.
There's been a rebellion in Almeria.
I've been told that cavalrymen
are the center of their forces.
There's 10,000 rean here.
Purchase all the horse feed
in the fief immediately.
At once.
Should I secure the
standard rations, as well?
If you'll entrust me with—
We don't need them.
War horses are not raised in Almeria.
According to my brother, Henry, the
rebels' horses were purchased elsewhere.
There's only so much horse feed
they could steal from citizens.
If we took the soldiers' rations,
they'd start looting...
Absolutely brilliant!
I'll get started at once!
This should make it a bit easier
for my brother to fight.
Translation:
Timing:
Editing:
Quality Control:
Becky Cottrill
Edgar Cruz
Gabriella Alabanza
S Bilyeu
Translation:
Timing:
Editing:
Quality Control:
Becky Cottrill
Edgar Cruz
Gabriella Alabanza
S Bilyeu